grayline.com 2017-05-23

# Privacy Policy

Gray Line Corporation, a Maryland non-stock corporation, knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This notice describes our privacy policy. By visiting web sites owned and/or operated by Gray Line Corporation and/or sites operated by Gray Line Licensees and linked to a site operated by Gray Line, (“Sites”) you are accepting the practices described in this privacy notice.

**About the Gray Line Corporation.**

The Gray Line Corporation (“Gray Line”) has its principal office in Denver, Colorado. As a Maryland non-stock corporation, Gray Line is the owner, and licensor of registered trademarks, trade names, service marks, designs and logos, which are used in connection with sightseeing, charter, transfer, destination management, package tour, attraction ticketing and other travel services (“Services”). Independent businesses operating under License from Gray Line within a geographic territory, known as Licensees, conduct these Services. As such, Gray Line does not itself provide any Services. Rather, it facilitates and communicates content, features, promotions, and the ability to make a reservation and/or purchase tickets for the Licensee providing the Services.

The information we learn from visitors to our Sites helps us personalize and continually improve your user experience. The remainder of this policy describes our information and handling practices in detail.

**When you are just visiting us.**

You can always visit our Sites without revealing who you are or providing any personal information. When you visit our Sites or visit our Sites through one of our independent Licensee sites, we do collect usage information (session data), but it is anonymous and does not link to you as an individual. We use session data to better understand things like how our Sites are being navigated, how many visitors arrive at specific pages, the length and frequency of stays at our Sites, the variety of searches of our Sites’ databases, the types of browsers and computer operating systems used by our visitors and the Internet Protocol addresses from which our visitors connect to our Sitess. We use this information to improve our Sites’ content and ease of use.

**Cookies.**

We may place a "cookie" on your personal computer. A cookie is a small piece of text stored on your computer by your web browser. Cookies help us recognize you when you visit our Sites again. We use cookies on our Sites to collect session data for several purposes to personalize and improve your individual viewing experiences on our Sites. For example, we use cookies to keep track of your use of our Sites, gather data to improve the content of our Sites, provide information that may be of interest to you and improve the security of your experience with us. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. However, you can set your browser preferences to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the sites you visit. If you decide not to accept our cookies, you will still be able to access those parts of the Gray Line Sites that are available to the general public, but you may not be able to use certain features designed to enhance your experience or access certain services we may offer.

We may also have third party advertisers ("Advertisers") on the Sites. These Advertisers may use cookies to track session data about the ads you have seen and those you appeared interested in. We do not share any personal information about you with these Advertisers unless you give permission to do so separate from any permission you provide during the registration process or in purchasing tickets. However, these Advertisers may have other sources of information in their own privacy practices. These Advertisers may also used combined information about your visits to the Gray Line Sites and other sites in order to provide advertisements about related goods and services that you may be interested in.

**When you decide to register with us.**

If you decide to register on a Gray Line Site and/or purchase tickets through our Sites, we will collect personal information about you that you voluntarily share with us. We collect personal information that is necessary for us to provide you with the Services offered on the Sites. As mentioned, this personal information includes things like your name, e-mail and mailing address and telephone number. You may be required to provide identifier information and select a password that will be required to gain access to portions of our Sites.

**Who will the information be shared with, if anyone?**

When you purchase tickets through the Sites, we provide information about you to our independent Licensees, Affiliated Licensees or other involved third parties. Occasionally, Gray Line Corporation will conduct (or use an unrelated third party to act on its behalf for) market research surveys, contest entry processing or other projects. Gray Line Corporation may also disclose user information in special cases when Gray Line has reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or initiate legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with Gray Line's rights or property, other Gray Line Licensees or Affiliated Licensees, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Gray Line may also disclose user information when it believes, in good faith, that the law requires such disclosure. 

**Affiliated Businesses.**

We work closely with our affiliated partners and Licensees, an example of which is the American Automobile Association ("AAA"). In certain cases, these businesses may offer their own products or services. In the event a Site provides a link to other sites, please note that such sites do not operate under this Privacy Policy. We recommend you examine the privacy statements posted on those other websites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information. The Gray Line Corporation is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites or for the privacy policies and practices of our affiliated partners and Licensees whose sites are not directly linked to a Gray Line operated web Sites.

**Online surveys, contests and promotional information.**

We value your business, comments and opinions. From time-to-time, we may invite you, as a user of our Sites, to participate in online surveys, but the choice will be yours. Each time you purchase, book or reserve services through the Sites, we may ask for feedback on your experience. Your participation in these surveys will be on an anonymous basis, unless we tell you otherwise and up-front. From time to time, we may also provide you with information on our products, services and or promotional information we think might be of interest to you. ** **

**Opt-Out.**

At any time, you may unsubscribe to the Gray Line Sites and stop receiving advertisements, updates and promotions. You may do so by notifying us at info@grayline.com.

**When you purchase, book or reserve services through  the Gray Line Sites.**

The Gray Line Corporation has entered into a strategic relationship with Travel UCD Limited (“Tour CMS”), a limited company registered under in England and Wales to use their confidential and proprietary reservations and ticketing system for the Sites.

Should you decide to purchase services through the Gray Line Sites, all information provided is encrypted. This encryption ensures that all data is transmitted from your browser to our servers at the highest levels of protection available today. In addition, any payment via credit card made through the Sites complies with the Payment Card Industry Standard Data Security Standard Requirements (“PCI DSS”). Depending on the services you purchase on our sites, your credit card statement will show charges processed by either “grayline.com”, the legal name of the company operating as the Gray Line Licensee, or of an authorized third party payment processor such as Trust My Travel or PayPal. While we will do everything we can to protect your privacy, it is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your confidential information, especially when using public or shared computers. 

**Conditions of use, notices and revisions.**

If you choose to visit the Sites, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this notice. If you are visiting a Site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, but please be assured that we take steps to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Policy. In the event a privacy dispute arises, by using the Sites, you agree to binding arbitration before the American Arbitration Association in Denver, Colorado. 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may update this Privacy Policy in the future. We will notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by placing a prominent notice on our website.

It is our sincere hope that you will avail yourselves of the opportunities presented through the Gray Line Sites. We will use our best efforts to provide you with the best possible tours, attractions and other services anywhere in the world you wish to go, as provided by our independent Gray Line Licensees. If you have any questions of the Gray Line Corporation or about this privacy policy, please direct them to info@grayline.com.

**Last updated:  **February 18, 2012
